newyorklife.com 2001-10-19

# New York Life Privacy Policy

|   
---  

| | |   

New York Life Online Privacy Policy   
(Effective as of April 1, 2001) 

We know that the privacy of your personal information is important to you. That's why the New York Life Family of Companies* wants you to know how we protect your privacy and the measures we take to safeguard your information. 

We have built our business on a foundation of integrity, honesty, and trust. These values are reflected in our longstanding commitment to protect your privacy. 

On www.newyorklife.com we strive to provide you with the most comprehensive and dependable source of life insurance and financial products information on the Web. You can access this information on our various sites with complete anonymity. Whether researching our products and services, using our planning tools, or accessing our educational content, you need provide no personal information whatsoever. Whenever you do supply personal information, such as your name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address, it is kept secure and used solely to answer your inquiry, comply with your request, or supply you with information about new products and services to help you meet your needs. 

Our Online Privacy Pledge  
To meet our users' needs with insurance and financial products and services, we depend on certain information. In gathering and maintaining this information, we pledge to 

  * Collect only the information we need to deliver superior products and services to you.
  * Prevent unauthorized access to your information.
  * Refuse to disclose your health information to third parties for marketing purposes without your consent.
  * Require companies that help us service your policy or account to protect your information in accordance with strict privacy standards.
  * Maintain control over the confidentiality of your personal information and give you a choice with regard to having your information shared with other companies for marketing purposes.
  * Maintain up-to-date privacy notices on our Web sites.

Our Information Practices  
The following policies and procedures protect the privacy of your information: 

Categories of Information We May Collect  
In the normal course of business we may collect the following types of information: 

  * Information you provide on applications and other forms (including name, address, income and other household information)
  * Data about your transactions with us (such as the type of products you have purchased and your account status)
  * Information gathered on our Web sites through online forms and site visit data collected through the use of information-collecting devices known as "cookies"
  * Health information, collected with your authorization, if you apply for products such as life insurance or long term care insurance.

Safeguarding Your Information  
Access to information gathered on our Web sites is limited to personnel who need the information to perform their job responsibilities. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that meet or exceed state and federal regulations. We continually update and improve our security standards, procedures, and technology to protect against unauthorized access to your confidential information. 

How We Use Your Information  
We may share your personal information within the New York Life Family or with non-affiliated companies as described below. 

  * We may share your information within the New York Life Family as permitted by law, including for routine business administration.
  * We may share information with non-affiliated companies as allowed by law, such as firms that perform services on our behalf including administering and marketing our products. We require these companies to meet strict privacy standards.
  * We may disclose information to non-affiliated entities when required by law, such as to respond to a subpoena, to prevent fraud, or to comply with an inquiry by a governmental agency.
  * Health Information Practices \- We will not share your health information for marketing purposes without your consent.

If you are a customer of the New York Life Family, and you use any of our service areas to change your accounts or account information, we will handle that information in accordance with our Customer Privacy Policy, which you can access by clicking here.

Keeping Up-To-Date With Our Privacy Policy  
This privacy policy takes effect April 1, 2001. You can always review the current privacy policy from the front page of the site, www.newyorklife.com. 

* The New York Life Family of Companies (also referred to as "the New York Life Family," "we," "our," or "us" throughout this notice) currently includes the following affiliates and funds: 

| New York Life Insurance Company | New York Life Benefit Services LLC  
---|---  
New York Life Insurance and Annuity Corporation | New York Life Trust Company  
New York Life International, Inc. | New York Life Trust Company, FSB  
New York Life Investment Management LLC | NYLIFE Administration Corp.  
Eagle Strategies Corp. | NYLIFE Distributors Inc.  
Eclipse Funds | NYLIFE Insurance Company of Arizona  
MainStay Funds | NYLIFE Securities INC.  
MainStay Shareholders Services LLC | NYLIM Service Company LLC  
MainStay VP Series Fund, Inc. | NYLINK Insurance Agencies  
  
If you would like more detailed information about this site's privacy practices, please click here.
